<Document>
[head=3][color=#ff0000]WARNING: You must be 18 or older to play. Users under 18 will be banned immediately.[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c][head=3]Erotic Roleplay (ERP), erotic content, and 18+ sexual and non-sexual content are allowed on this server.[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c][head=3]Admins may within reason act outside of the rules listed below and will be held accountable through use of the admin code of conduct. This mandate is formally known as "Rule 0”. It covers common sense and allows administrators to make judgements to situations not explicitly covered by these rules.[/head][/color]

[color=#ffff00]If you have any questions about these rules, please use the Admin Help menu (AHelp) by pressing the F1 key, or clicking the "AHelp" button on top of your screen (the one with a danger symbol on it).[/color]

[color=#ffff00]If you are ever unsure of something, or got a particular idea, ask an Admin via AHelp. No response does not equate to permission.[/color]

Each section contains its own list of rules. Click on the section name to view the full version.

  - [textlink="Section 1. Out Of Character" link="RuleC1"]
  - [textlink="Section 2. Consent" link="RuleC2"]
  - [textlink="Section 3. Metagaming Rules" link="RuleC3"]
  - [textlink="Section 4. Powergaming" link="RuleC4"]
  - [textlink="Section 5. Roleplay and Characters" link="RuleC5"]
  - [textlink="Section 6. Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) and NSFW" link="RuleC6"]
  - [textlink="Section 7. Death and New Life" link="RuleC7"]
  - [textlink="Section 8. End-of-Round (EOR) and Evacuation" link="RuleC8"]
  - [textlink="Section 9. General Roles and Jobs" link="RuleC9"]
  - [textlink="Section 10. Command and Security" link="RuleC10"]
  - [textlink="Section 11. Antagonists" link="RuleC11"]


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 1: Out Of Character[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]1.1[/color] Be polite, civil and respectful towards other players and admins.

[color=#a4885c]1.2[/color] Hate speech is forbidden.

[color=#a4885c]1.3[/color] Do not disconnect during an AHelp in progress (if connection is lost due to Internet issues, open a ticket on the Discord ASAP).

[color=#a4885c]1.4[/color] It is forbidden to livestream rounds to others or share recorded gameplay outside of Euphoria Station without consent of all parties involved.

[color=#a4885c]1.5[/color] Ghosting with the sole intent of spying on other people's personal activities (especially ERP) is not permitted.

[color=#a4885c]1.6[/color] Do not spam or advertise (either other servers, or in general).


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 2: Consent[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]2.1[/color] Both roleplay and ERP require all players involved to be consenting. If your consent is not respected, immediately AHelp or open a ticket.

[color=#a4885c]2.2[/color] Roleplay may occur under implied consent when all players involved engage in roleplay that suggests mutual willingness with no OOC objections raised during or immediately after the interaction.

[color=#a4885c]2.3[/color] It is your responsibility to keep your consent preferences up to date.

[color=#a4885c]2.4[/color] While usage of kinks or sex mechanics for gameplay or non-sexual roleplay purposes is not forbidden per se, you must seek consent from everybody who could be exposed to it.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 3: Metagaming[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]3.1[/color] Do not metagame (using information that your character has no way of knowing or obtaining).

[color=#a4885c]3.2[/color] Do not metagrudge nor metafriend (treating unfairly a character solely based on the out of character relationship with the player).

[color=#a4885c]3.3[/color] Players are allowed to retain and share knowledge of past experiences and prior shifts.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 4: Powergaming[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]4.1[/color] Do not powergame (minmaxing to try and achieve the best possible results to the point of being detrimental to roleplay, i.e carrying an armoury around as HoS, utilising storage inside of storage to bypass getting a bluespace bag)

[color=#a4885c]4.2[/color] We allow Greytiding within reason (gathering tools, materials in maintenance) but do not permit the construction of weapons, harmful buildings, or the hoarding of equipment.

[color=#a4885c]4.3[/color] As a non-antagonist, do not intentionally hide antagonist objective items without reason. Reasonable places to keep objectives are on one’s person, or in the intended room.

[color=#a4885c]4.4[/color] While it is allowed for the crew to know the details around the various antagonist functions, it is forbidden to act on that information without valid motive.

[color=#a4885c]4.5[/color] Do not validhunt (Non-Security personnel should not actively seek out and try to attack, detain or kill antagonists and hostile NPCs that are not threatening you immediately).

[color=#a4885c]4.6[/color] Do not intentionally breach nor metagame roleplay in order to gain unfair advantages (such as typebaiting, faking RP interactions then attacking without provocation).

[color=#a4885c]4.7[/color] Do not dismantle or damage important, irreplaceable station infrastructure. If you are unsure or got a particular idea, ask in AHelp for approval.

[color=#a4885c]4.8[/color] Try to avoid minmaxing (becoming a detriment to your job or to roleplay i.e. not salving until the industrial board)

[color=#a4885c]4.9[/color] Station departments are expected to be working together and collaborating. Avoid self-isolating "independency" tactics and behaviours


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 5: Roleplay and Characters[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]5.1[/color] You are expected to roleplay and maintain a good level and quality of roleplay.

[color=#a4885c]5.2[/color] Prioritize making the game fun for everyone, not just yourself.

[color=#a4885c]5.3[/color] Your character is a separate entity from you, the player. Do not make your character a self-insert.

[color=#a4885c]5.4[/color] Do not make yourself a major problem, annoyance, or disruption for the crew while not being an antagonist.

[color=#a4885c]5.5[/color] Do not play excessively hostile characters, excluding antagonists (consistent verbal assault, degradation, verbal antagonism).

[color=#a4885c]5.6[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels.

[color=#a4885c]5.7[/color] Escalate issues IC through IC means (i.e cap to centcom) before attempting to AHelp an issue (i.e. security breaking SoP).

[color=#a4885c]5.8[/color] Do not loot AFK players as a non-antagonist non-security role.

[color=#a4885c]5.9[/color] Dismantling, scrapping or destruction of station property without a reasonable emergency, urgency or need for it is strongly discouraged (disassembling an escape pod for a shittle is not reasonable emergency, dismantling chairs to complete the PA for power is)

[color=#a4885c]5.10[/color] Players are allowed and even encouraged to engage in creative gimmicks, mischief, hijinks and ideas, so long it doesn't cross the border into disruptive behaviour (self-antag, powergaming, metagaming, etc.)

[color=#a4885c]5.11[/color] Suicide, self-harm, and other related roleplay is forbidden.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 6: Erotic-Role-Play (ERP) and NSFW[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]6.1[/color] Do not kinkshame.

[color=#a4885c]6.2[/color] All underage and ageplay content is forbidden.

[color=#a4885c]6.3[/color] Any creature or being that is not player-controlled is to be considered off-limits for any form of ERP (they must pass the Harkness test).

[color=#a4885c]6.4[/color] Roleplay of controversial, heavy themes and topics that would make most people uncomfortable (extreme topics) must be kept out of the public eye and ear and make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper).

[color=#a4885c]6.5[/color] Active ERP must make use of subtle verbs (subtle emote, subtle LOOC, and whisper), if done outside of an explicitly marked ERP area, players may ask those engaging to move to a private area.

[color=#a4885c]6.6[/color] Public ERP is allowed, if it is explicitly marked, and not involving extreme themes, players may use regular emotes here, it is up to other players to move away from these areas if they are made uncomfortable.

[color=#a4885c]6.7[/color] Do not use ERP as bait for kill objectives, unless done with OOC consent of all parties involved.

[color=#a4885c]6.8[/color] Your job comes before ERP, if required you must stop a scene to do your duty. Select passenger if you wish to ERP in peace.

[color=#a4885c]6.9[/color] Do not spam or pollute radio channels (including the telepath channel) with NSFW topics.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 7: Death and New Life[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]7.1[/color] Characters maintain all memory up until death.

[color=#a4885c]7.2[/color] Characters’ perception during a critical state is impaired (no distinct names, faces, objects, locations).

[color=#a4885c]7.3[/color] If a player is brought back to life by means of cloning, they lose all the memories that have been acquired so far into shift.

[color=#a4885c]7.4[/color] If your character dies or enters cryostasis beyond the point of no return, you normally cannot respawn as the same character. Seek permission from an admin if you need or wish to do so.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 8: End-of-Round (EOR) and Evacuation[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]8.1[/color] Conflicts in end-of-round Safe Havens (such as the evacuation shuttle, Central Command, and hallways leading to evac) must remain verbal and non-violent. Exception is made for Security.

[color=#a4885c]8.2[/color] Antagonist roles are allowed to pursue non-violent objectives in Safe Havens.

[color=#a4885c]8.3[/color] Evac should not be called nor recalled without reasonable motive.

[color=#a4885c]8.4[/color] Antagonists are not allowed to call nor to recall evac.

[color=#a4885c]8.5[/color] Active hostile nuclear operatives may board the evac shuttle to retrieve the nuclear authentication disk, and may use violence providing it does not cause unnecessary casualties or structural damage.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 9: General Roles and Jobs[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]9.1[/color] If you choose a job on shift, you are required to participate in that role.

[color=#a4885c]9.2[/color] If you are banned from a role or a department you may not seek or accept promotions into roles you are banned from.

[color=#a4885c]9.3[/color] Try not to engage in tasks that do not fall under the purview of your job.

[color=#a4885c]9.4[/color] By picking the prisoner role, you have chosen to roleplay as a prisoner NOT an antagonist. This includes (but is not limited to) any attempt at breaking out without reasonable emergency or need or admin approval, staging riots, or killing Security or fellow prisoners.

[color=#a4885c]9.5[/color] Department strikes require explicit administrator approval.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 10: Command and Security[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]10.1[/color] Security and Command roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay.

[color=#a4885c]10.2[/color] Command and Security are required to know Security Standard Operating Procedures, Alert Procedure, and Company Policy.

[color=#a4885c]10.3[/color] Do not abuse your position of power (unless this is being done privately and with consent of all parties involved).

[color=#a4885c]10.4[/color] Follow reasonable escalation (i.e attempt an arrest with non-lethals before opening fire with lethals on someone, responding to lethals with lethals etc).

[color=#a4885c]10.5[/color] If you are playing a Command role inform the rest of the Command before cryoing or disconnecting.


[color=#ffff00][head=3]Section 11: Antagonists[/head][/color]

[color=#a4885c]11.1[/color] The role of an antagonist is to make the game more fun, exciting and interesting, not miserable, unfun and frustrating. As such try to play out the role focusing not on winning, but on making things more thrilling and entertaining.

[color=#a4885c]11.2[/color] Antagonistic roles are held to a higher standard of roleplay.

[color=#a4885c]11.3[/color] Damage by any antagonist role must be proportional and pertinent to their related objectives.

[color=#a4885c]11.4[/color] Antagonists must follow a 30-minute grace period from round start (deliberately completing objectives or conducting disruptive behaviour that could be used to complete your objectives).

[color=#a4885c]11.5[/color] Intentional round removal is forbidden, excluding “kill or maroon” objectives.

[color=#a4885c]11.6[/color] Seek admin permission to play a normally hostile ghost role as friendly.

[color=#a4885c]11.7[/color] Antagonists may collaborate if they belong to the same faction and do have a reasonable mutual deal established (i.e. a syndie cannot mow down a station with a nukie for the hypospray).

[color=#a4885c]11.8[/color] An antagonist may create their own objectives (pinktexting) if they do not wish to follow their current objectives, and the intended outcome is to generate unique roleplay opportunities. All former antagonist rules must be followed, if you are unsure seek admin approval.
</Document>
